<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="exameConsciencia">Conscience examination</string>
	<string name="exame">Exam</string>
	<string name="confissao">Confession</string>
	<string name="confissao.aviso"> WARNING: Your conscience examination will belost by privacy issues, if you leave this screen!</string>
	<string name="confissao.ritoInicial">
		Bless me father for I have sinned.
		There is [time] I did my last confession. My sins are as follows …
	</string>
	<string-array name="confissao_mandamentos">
		<item>First Commandment: I am the Lord thy God, Thou shalt have nogods strangers before me (including sins against the Faith, Hope andCharity)</item>
		<item>Second Commandment: Thou shalt not take the Name of the Lordthy God in will.</item>
		<item>Third Commandment: Remember thou keep holy the Sabbath Day</item>
		<item>Fourth Commandment: Honor thy father and thy mother.</item>
		<item>Fifth Commandment: Thou shalt not kill.</item>
		<item>Sixth and Ninth Commandments: Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou shalt not covet neighbor\'s wife.</item>
		<item>Seventh and Tenth Commandments: Thou shalt not steal. Do not covet the goods thy neighbor\'s.</item>
		<item>Eighth Commandment: Thou shalt not bear false witness againstyour neighbor.</item>
	</string-array> 
	<string-array name="confissao_primeiroMandamento">
		<item>I have neglected the knowledge of my faith, as the Catechismteaches, as the Apostles\' Creed, the Ten Commandments, the SevenSacraments, the word of our Father, etc</item>
		<item>I have deliberately doubted any of the teachings of the Church or denied it</item>
		<item>I took part in an act of Catholic worship is not </item>
		<item>I am a member of some non-Catholic religious organization, secret society or group of anti-Catholic people</item>
		<item>I have read, with awareness of what I did, some heretical, blasphemous or anti-Catholic literature</item>
		<item>I have practiced any superstitions (such as horoscopes, fortune, Ouija board, etc)</item>
		<item>I forgot to recommend me daily to God</item>
		<item>I had stopped praying faithful in my daily prayers</item>
		<item>I abused the sacraments in any way</item>
		<item>I mocked God, Our Lady, the Saints, the Church, the Sacraments, or other holy things</item>
		<item>I was guilty of great irreverence in church. For example, conversation, bad behavior, or how I was dressed</item>
		<item>I was indifferent to my Catholic Faith - believing that a person can be saved in any religion or all religions are equal</item>
		<item>I took for granted the mercy of God some time</item>
		<item>I was despair of the mercy of God</item>
		<item>I lacked love for God or even hated Him</item>
		<item>I have given too much importance to any creature, activity, object or opinion</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_segundoMandamento">
		<item>I swore by God\'s name falsely, rashly or trivial and unimportant matters</item>
		<item>I murmured or complained against God (blasphemy)</item>
		<item>I cursed myself or another person or creature</item>
		<item>I have angered somebody or made him swear or blaspheme God</item>
		<item>I broke a promise to God</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_terceiroMandamento">
		<item>I missed Mass on Sundays or Holy Days of the obligation</item>
		<item>I arrived late for Mass on Sundays and Holy Days of obligation, or left early because of unimportant matters</item>
		<item>I made other people miss, leave or arrive late for Mass on Sundays and Days of Saints guard</item>
		<item>I have been willfully distracted during Mass</item>
		<item>I have done or commanded unnecessary servile work on Sunday or Holy Days of Obligation</item>
		<item>I have bought or sold anything without the need for Sunday and Saints guard</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_quartoMandamento">
		<item>I disobeyed my parents, lacked respect, or neglected to assist them in their needs or refused to do so</item>
		<item>I have shown irreverence towards people in positions of authority</item>
		<item>I insulted or mocked priests or others consecrated to God</item>
		<item>I had few reverence for the elderly</item>
		<item>I mistreated my wife or my children</item>
		<item>I was disobedient to my husband, or lacked respect for him</item>
		<item>I neglected the needs of my children</item>
		<item>I have not attepted to baptize my children early </item>
		<item>I neglected the right of religious education of my children</item>
		<item>I allowed my children to neglect their religious duties</item>
		<item>I stopped to watch the ones whom my children walk</item>
		<item>I have failed to discipline my children when they needed discipline</item>
		<item>I gave bad example to my children </item>
		<item>I scandalized my children, arguing with my spouse in front of them</item>
		<item>I scandalized my children saying obscenities in front of them</item>
		<item>I failed to keep modesty in my house</item>
		<item>I let my children to wear immodest clothing</item>
		<item>I denied my children the freedom to marry or follow a religious vocation</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_quintoMandamento">
		<item>I procured, desired, or hastened the death or injury of someone</item>
		<item>I fed hatred for someone</item>
		<item>I oppressed somebody</item>
		<item>I wished to avenge me or someone</item>
		<item>I caused enmity between people</item>
		<item>I quarreled or fought with someone</item>
		<item>I wished evil to someone</item>
		<item>I wanted to injure or mistreat someone, or tried to do it</item>
		<item>I refused to talk to or held resentment to someone</item>
		<item>I rejoiced schadenfreude</item>
		<item>I have been jealous or envious of someone</item>
		<item>I tried to or did myself an abortion or counseled anyone to do an abortion</item>
		<item>I mutilated my body unnecessarily in any way</item>
		<item>I have consented to thoughts of suicide, I have wanted to kill myself or attempted suicide</item>
		<item>I have been drunk or used illegal drugs</item>
		<item>I ate too much or in a careless manner</item>
		<item>I failed to follow the rules of charity</item>
		<item>I harmed somebody\'s soul, especially children, giving scandal or bad example</item>
		<item>I have hurt my soul, exposing them intentionally and without need to temptations, bad TV shows, reprehensible music, etc…</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_sextoEnonoMandamento">
		<item>I have denied my spouse of his or her marriage rights</item>
		<item>I have practiced birth control (pills, devices, interruption)</item>
		<item>I have abused my marriage rights in any other way</item>
		<item>I have committed adultery or fornication (premarital sex) </item>
		<item>I made any unnatural sin against nature (homosexuality or lesbianism, etc…)</item>
		<item>I have impurely sinned against myself (masturbation)</item>
		<item>I consented to impure thoughts, or had pleasure in them.</item>
		<item>I consented to impure desires to someone, or wanted consciously see or do anything impure</item>
		<item>I consciously gave me sexual pleasure, complete or incomplete</item>
		<item>I was an occasion of sin for others by wearing tight, revealing or immodest clothes</item>
		<item>I deliberately or through carelessness provoked impure thoughts or desires in another person</item>
		<item>I have read indecent literature or looked at bad pictures</item>
		<item>I watched films or television programs with suggestive or pornographic material or permitted my children to do so</item>
		<item>I used indecent language or told indecent stories</item>
		<item>I heard indecent stories with goodwill</item>
		<item>I have bragged to me of my sins, or delight in remembering old sins</item>
		<item>I have been in lewd company</item>
		<item>I have consented to impure glances</item>
		<item>I have neglected to control my imagination</item>
		<item>I ceased to pray in order to banish evil thoughts andtemptations</item>
		<item>I have not avoided sloth, gluttony, idleness, and occasions for impurity</item>
		<item>I have went to immodest or indecent dances or plays</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_setimoEdecimoMandamento">
		<item>I stole something</item>
		<item>I damaged someone\'s property</item>
		<item>I ruined by neglection the property of others</item>
		<item>I was negligent in the stewardship of money or property of others</item>
		<item>I have cheated or defrauded others </item>
		<item>I have played too much </item>
		<item>I refused to pay a debt or neglected a payment</item>
		<item>I have acquired anything known to be stolen</item>
		<item>I failed to return something borrowed</item>
		<item>I have theft my boss, not working as expected of me</item>
		<item>I cheated the wages of my employees</item>
		<item>I refused to help anyone in urgent need of help, or neglected to do so</item>
		<item>I failed to return what one has stolen, or obtained by or embusted fraud (ask the priest how to make restitution or how to return to the owner what you took)</item>
		<item>I envy someone for having something that I don\'t have</item>
		<item>I envied the goods of one</item>
		<item>I have been stingy</item>
		<item>I have given too much importance to material goods and comforts</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_oitavoMandamento">
		<item>I lied about somebody (calumny)</item>
		<item>My lies caused somebody spiritual or material damage</item>
		<item>I rashly judged anyone (that is, firmly believed, without sufficient evidence, they were guilty of some moral defect or crime)</item>
		<item>I injured the good name of someone by revealing faults while hiding the truth (slander)</item>
		<item>I have revealed the sins of someone else</item>		
		<item>I was guilty of doing intrigues (ie, to say something unfavorable that someone said someone else, to create enmity between them)</item>
		<item>I gave credit or supported the dissemination of scandals</item>
		<item>I swore or signed false documents</item>
		<item>I am critical, unnecessarily negative or lack charity in my conversations</item>
	</string-array>
</resources>
