<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="exameConsciencia">Examination of Conscience</string>
	<string name="exame">Exam</string>
	<string name="confissao">Confession</string>
	<string name="confissao.aviso"> WARNING: Your examination of conscience will be
		lost by privacy issues, if you leave this screen!
	</string>
	<string name="confissao.ritoInicial">
		Bless me father for I have sinned
		There is [time] I
		did my
		last confession. My sins are as follows ...
	</string>
	<string-array name="confissao_mandamentos">
		<item>First Commandment: I am the Lord thy God, Thou shalt have no
			gods strangers before me (including sins against the Faith, Hope and
			Charity)
		</item>
		<item>Second Commandment: Thou shalt not take the Name of the Lord
			thy
			God in will.
		</item>
		<item>Third Commandment: Remember thou keep holy the Sabbath Day
		</item>
		<item>Fourth Commandment: Honor thy father and thy mother.</item>
		<item>Fifth Commandment: Thou shalt not kill.</item>
		<item>Sixth and Ninth Commandments: Thou shalt not commit adultery.
			Thou shalt not covet neighbor\'s wife.
		</item>
		<item>Seventh and Tenth Commandments: Thou shalt not steal. Do not
			covet the goods thy neighbor\'s.
		</item>
		<item>Eighth Commandment: Thou shalt not bear false witness against
			your neighbor.
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_primeiroMandamento">
		<item>neglected the knowledge of my faith, as the Catechism
			teaches,
			as
			the Apostles\' Creed, the Ten Commandments, the Seven
			Sacraments,
			the
			Our Father, etc.
		</item>
		<item>Have I deliberately doubted any of the teachings of
			Church or
			denied
		</item>
		<item>I took part in an act of Catholic worship is not </item>
		<item>I am a member of some non-Catholic religious organization, the
			secret society or a group of anti-Catholic
		</item>
		<item>ever read, with awareness of what she did, some literature
			heretical, blasphemous or anti-Catholic
		</item>
		<item>I practiced any superstitions (such as horoscopes, fortune,
			Ouija board, etc.).
		</item>
		<item>leave to recommend me daily to God</item>
		<item>stop praying faithful to my daily prayers</item>
		<item>I abused the sacraments in any way</item>
		<item>mock God of Our Lady, the Saints, the Church, the
			Sacraments, or
			other holy things
		</item>
		<item>I was guilty of great irreverence in church, for example,
			conversation, behavior, or how he was dressed
		</item>
		<item>I was indifferent to my Catholic Faith - believing that a
			person
			can be saved in any religion or all religions
			are equal
		</item>
		<item>assumed at any time had guaranteed the mercy of God</item>
		<item> despair of the mercy of God </item>
		<item>I hated God</item>
		<item> I given too much importance to any creature, activity, object
			or opinion
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_segundoMandamento">
		<item>I swear by God\'s name falsely, rashly or trivial and
			unimportant
			matters
		</item>
		<item>I murmured or complained against God (blasphemy) </item>
		<item>cursed me to myself, or another person or creature
		</item>
		<item>Have I angered, to make them swear or blaspheme God </item>
		<item> broke a promise to God </item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_terceiroMandamento">
		<item>I missed Mass on Sundays or Holy Days of </item>
		<item>I arrived late for Mass on Sundays and Holy Days of obligation,
			or left early because of me
		</item>
		<item>I made other people miss Mass on Sundays and Days
			Saints guard,
			or leave early or be late for Mass
		</item>
		<item>been willfully distracted during Mass</item>
		<item>I done or commanded unnecessary servile work on Sunday or
			Holy
			Days of Obligation
		</item>
		<item>buy or sell anything without the need for Sunday and
			Saints guard
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_quartoMandamento">
		<item> I disobeyed my parents, they lack respect, I neglected
			to assist
			them in their needs or build your
			will or I refused to do so
		</item>
		<item> shown irreverence towards people in positions of
			authority
		</item>
		<item> or insulted I maligned priests or others
			consecrated to God
		</item>
		<item>I had less reverence for the elderly </item>
		<item>I mistreated my wife or my children </item>
		<item>I was disobedient to my husband, or lacks respect </item>
		<item>I neglected their material needs of my children </item>
		<item>not tried to baptize my children early </item>
		<item>neglect the religious education of my children right </item>
		<item>I allowed my children neglecting their religious duties</item>
		<item> I stopped to watch the companies with whom my children walk
		</item>
		<item> to discipline them when I left my children need such
		</item>
		<item> Gave bad example to my children </item>
		<item>scandalized my children, arguing with my spouse in front
			their
		</item>
		<item>scandalized my saying obscenities in front </item>
		<item>I left to keep modesty in my house </item>
		<item>Let my children to wear immodest clothing </item>
		<item>I denied my children the freedom to marry or follow a
			religious
			vocation
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_quintoMandamento">
		<item>procured, desired, or hastened the death or injury of someone
		</item>
		<item>fed hatred for someone </item>
		<item>oppressed anyone </item>
		<item>wished to avenge me </item>
		<item>caused enmity between others </item>
		<item>quarreled or fought with someone </item>
		<item>wished evil to someone </item>
		<item>wanted to injure or mistreat someone, or tried to do it </item>
		<item>I refuse to talk to someone, or someone of resentment </item>
		<item>I rejoiced schadenfreude </item>
		<item> I been jealous or envious of someone </item>

		<item>I tried or an abortion, counseled or anyone else to do
		</item>
		<item>mutilated my body unnecessarily in any way </item>
		<item>consented to thoughts of suicide, I wanted to kill myself or
			attempted suicide
		</item>
		<item>me become drunk or used illegal drugs </item>
		<item>I ate too much, or not as careless enough </item>
		<item>I failed to correct within the rules of charity </item>
		<item>I harmed anyone\'s soul, especially children, giving
			scandal
			through bad example
		</item>
		<item> I hurt my soul, exposing them intentionally and without
			need to
			temptations, and bad TV shows, music
			reprehensible, beaches, etc..
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_sextoEnonoMandamento">
		<item>I denied my spouse his or her marriage rights </item>
		<item> practiced birth control (pills, devices, interruption)
		</item>
		<item> I abused my marriage rights in any other way </item>
		<item> committed adultery or fornication (premarital sex) </item>
		<item> I made any unnatural sin against nature (homosexuality or
			lesbianism, etc.).
		</item>
		<item>impurely I have sinned against myself (masturbation) </item>
		<item>consented to impure thoughts, or had pleasure in them </item>
		<item>consented to impure desires to someone, or wanted
			consciously see
			or do anything impure
		</item>
		<item> consciously gave me sexual pleasure, complete or incomplete
		</item>
		<item> I was an occasion of sin for others by wearing tight,
			revealing
			or immodest
		</item>

		<item>I deliberately or through carelessness, which
			provoke impure
			thoughts or desires another person
		</item>
		<item> I read indecent literature or looked at bad pictures </item>
		<item> Saw films or television programs suggestive, or pornographic
			Internet, or permitted my children to do so
		</item>
		<item> I used indecent language or told indecent stories </item>

		<item>I heard stories indecent goodwill </item>
		<item> bragged to me of my sins, or delight in remembering sins
			old
		</item>
		<item> been in lewd company </item>
		<item> consented to impure glances </item>
		<item> I neglected to control my imagination </item>
		<item> ceased to pray at once to banish evil thoughts and
			temptations
		</item>
		<item> I avoided sloth, gluttony, idleness, and occasions for
			impurity
		</item>
		<item>I went to dances immodest or indecent plays </item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_setimoEdecimoMandamento">
		<item>I stole something? What, or how much </item>
		<item>I damaged anyone\'s property </item>
		<item>let it ruin by neglect, the property of others </item>
		<item>I was negligent in the stewardship of money or property of
			others
		</item>
		<item>I cheating or defrauded others </item>
		<item>I played too much </item>
		<item>I refused to pay any debt or neglected me in your payment
		</item>
		<item>acquired anything known to be stolen </item>
		<item>I failed to return something borrowed </item>
		<item>Theft my boss, not working as expected of me
		</item>
		<item>I cheated the wages of my employees </item>
		<item>I refused to help anyone in urgent need of help,
			or neglected to
			do so I
		</item>
		<item>I failed to return what they stole, or obtained by or embusted
			fraud (ask the priest how to make restitution, or
			that is, returning
			to the owner what it took)
		</item>
		<item>I envy someone for having something that I have not </item>
		<item>I envied the goods of one </item>
		<item>Have I been stingy
		</item>
		<item>I have given too much importance on material goods and comforts
		</item>
	</string-array>
	<string-array name="confissao_oitavoMandamento">
		<item>I lied about anyone (calumny) </item>
		<item>My lies caused them damage or
			spiritual
		</item>
		<item> I rashly judged anyone (that is,
			firmly believed, without
			sufficient evidence, they were guilty of
			some moral defect or crime)
		</item>
		<item> injured the good name of someone revealing faults but true
			hidden (slander)
		</item>
		<item> reveal the sins of someone else </item>		
		<item>I was guilty of doing intrigues (ie, to say something
			unfavorable that someone said
			someone else, to create enmity
			between them)
		</item>
		<item>Gave credit or supporting the dissemination of scandal about mynext
		</item>
		<item>I swore signed false documents or false </item>
		<item>I am critical or negative unnecessarily or miss to charity in
			my conversations
		</item>
	</string-array>
</resources>
