<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="donsEspiritoSanto">
        <item> 1 - Fortress </item>
        <item> 2 - Wisdom </item>
        <item> 3 - Science </item>
        <item> 4 - Council </item>
        <item> 5 - Understanding </item>
        <item> 6 - Mercy </item>
        <item> 7 - Fear God </item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="fortaleza.descricao"> 
		It is the gift to resist the lure, to be consistent with the Gospel, 
		to take risks in the struggle for justice, not fear martyrdom. 
		St. Paul relied on the gift of fortitude. He said: "If God is with us 
		who can be against us? "(Romans 8:31). 
    </string>
    <string name="sabedoria.descricao"> 
		It is the gift of perceiving right and wrong, 
		which facilitates and hinders the design of God. 
		For this gift does not seek the advantages of this world, but the 
		Supreme Good Life, which fills our hearts with peace 
		and makes us happy. Saith the Lord: 
		"Blessed is the man who found the wisdom … 
		It is more valuable than pearls "(cf. Prov 3:13-15). 
    </string>
    <string name="ciencia.descricao"> 
        It is the gift of knowing how to interpret and explain the Word of God. 
        For this gift, the Holy Spirit reveals the inside 
        God thought about us as "the mysteries of God 
        Nobody knows, unless the Holy Spirit "(1 Cor 2.10 to 15). 
    </string>
    <string name="conselho.descricao"> 
        It is the gift of discern paths and options, 
        guide to know and listen, to animate the faith and 
        the hope of the community. But the Lord 
        told him: "Do not be impressed by his 
        lovely aspect, because I have refused. 
        The man sees is not what matters: the man sees 
        face, but the Lord sees the heart "(1 Sam 16:7). 
    </string>
    <string name="entendimento.descricao"> 
        It is the gift of God which enlightens us to accept the truths revealed by God. 
		Even not understanding the mystery, we understand that there is our salvation, 
		because it comes from God who is infallible. The Lord said: 
		"I will give them an heart to know me and understand 
		I am the Lord "(Jer. 24.7). 
    </string>
    <string name="piedade.descricao"> 
        It is the gift of always being open to God\'s will, 
        trying to act as Jesus would act and identifying 
        next the face of Christ. 
        It is the gift for which the Holy Spirit gives us a taste 
        to love and serve God with joy. 
        "The kingdom of God is not food and drink, 
        but righteousness, peace and joy in the Holy Spirit "(Rom 14:17). 
    </string>
    <string name="temor.descricao"> 
        It does not mean "fear of God" 
        but fear of offending God. 
        He is our best friend, 
        We fear we will not 
        returning the love that is owed. 
        More than fear is respect and appreciation for God. 
        "Hear, O Israel: the Lord our God is one Lord. 
        Love the Lord your God with all thy heart, 
        with all thy soul and with all thy strength "(Dt 6:4-5). 
    </string>

</resources>