<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="oracao.santoexpedito.name">Prayer to Saint Expedite</string>
    <string name="oracao.santoexpedito">
		My Saint Expedite of urgent and just causes, please intercede for me with Our Lord Jesus Christ.
      Succor me in this hour of affliction and despair, my Saint Expedite. You who are a Holy warrior, You who are the Saint of the afflicted, You who are the Saint of the desperate, you who are the Saint of urgent causes, Protect me, Help me, Give me Strength, Courage and Serenity.

      Hear my plea. ____________ (Clearly express what you want, and ask him to find a way to get it to you.)

      My Saint Expedite, help me to prevail through these difficult hours, protect me from all those who want to harm me, respond to my plea with urgency. Bring me back to the state of peace and        tranquillity, my Saint Expedite. I will be grateful to you for the rest of my life and I will speak your name to all those who have faith.
     (Now promise to give Saint Expedite a specific offering when your desire is granted.)
     Amen.
    (Say one Our Father, one Holy Mary, and make the sign of the cross.)

    (Be sure to provide the offering you promised if Saint Expedite grants your petition)
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.meninojesusdepraga.name">Prayer to the Infant Jesus of Prague</string>
    <string name="oracao.meninojesusdepraga">
		O Jesus, Who said, "Ask and you shall receive, seek and you shall find, knock
and it shall be opened to you," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I knock, I seek, I ask that my prayer be answered.  (Mention your request)

      O Jesus, Who said, "All that you ask of the Father in My Name He will grant you," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I humbly and urgently ask Your Father in Your Name that my prayer be granted.  (Mention your request.)

      O Jesus, Who said, "Heaven and earth will pass away, but My word shall not pass," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I feel confident that my prayer will be granted.  (Mention your request)

      Amen
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saojorge.name">Prayer of Saint George</string>
    <string name="oracao.saojorge">
		O Saint George, my Holy Warrior, invincible faith
		in God, which brings
		your face in the hope and confidence, open my
		ways. I will walk
		dress and armed with your arms so that my feet do not
		have enemies
		reach me, and do not catch hands, with eyes to see, and I
		do not even
		thoughts may have to make me harm. Firearms my body
		not
		reach, knives and spears break without my body reach,
		ropes and chains
		to break out my body without the tie. glorious
		St. George, on behalf of
		God, extend your shield and your mighty
		weapons, defend me with your
		strength and greatness. Help me to overcome
		all despondency and achieve
		grace I ask (request).
		Give me courage and hope, strengthen my faith
		and auxiliai me this
		need.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saomiguel.name">Prayer of St. Michael the Archangel</string>
    <string name="oracao.saomiguel">
		Saint Michael the Archangel,
      defend us in battle.
      Be our protection against the wickedness and snares of the devil.
      May God rebuke him, we humbly pray;
      and do Thou, O Prince of the Heavenly Host -
      by the Divine Power of God -
      cast into hell, satan and all the evil spirits,
      who roam throughout the world seeking the ruin of souls.

      Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.almadecristo.name">Soul of Christ</string>
    <string name="oracao.almadecristo">
		Soul of Christ, santify me.
Body of Christ, save me.
Blood of Christ, inebriate me.
Water from the side of Christ, wash me.
Passion of Christ, strengthen me.
O good Jesus, hear me.
Within your wounds, hide me.
Never let me be separated from you.
From the malignant enemy, defend me.
At the hour of death, call me;
and bid me come to you.
That with your saints I may praise you
forever and ever.

Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saofrancisco.name">Prayer of St. Francis</string>
    <string name="oracao.saofrancisco">
		Lord, make me an instrument of your peace.
Where there is hatred, let me sow love;
where there is injury,pardon;
where there is doubt, faith;
where there is despair, hope;
where there is darkness, light;
and where there is sadness, joy.


O Divine Master, grant that I may not so much seek
to be consoled as to console;
to be understood as to understand;
to be loved as to love.
For it is in giving that we receive;
it is in pardoning that we are pardoned;
and it is in dying that we are born to eternal life. Amen 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.avemaria.name">Hail Mary</string>
    <string name="oracao.avemaria">
Hail Mary, full of grace.
Our Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.painosso.name">Our Father</string>
    <string name="oracao.painosso">
Our Father, Who is in heaven,
Holy is Your Name;
Your kingdom come,
Your will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our sins,
as we forgive those who sin against us;
and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.salveRainha.name">Hail Holy Queen</string>
    <string name="oracao.salveRainha">
		Hail, holy Queen, Mother of mercy, hail, our life, our sweetness and our hope. To thee do we cry, poor banished children of Eve: to thee do we send up our sighs, mourning and weeping in this vale of tears. Turn then, most gracious Advocate, thine eyes of mercy toward us, and after this our exile, show unto us the blessed fruit of thy womb, Jesus, O merciful, O loving, O sweet Virgin Mary! Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.credo.name">The Apostles Creed</string>
    <string name="oracao.credo">
I believe in God,
the Father Almighty,
Creator of Heaven and earth.

I believe in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord,
who was conceived by the Holy Spirit,
born of the Virgin Mary,
suffered under Pontius Pilate,
was crucified, died and was buried.
He descended to the dead.
On the third day, He rose again.
He ascended to Heaven and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.

I believe in the Holy Spirit,
the Holy Catholic Church,
the communion of saints,
the forgiveness of sins,
the resurrection of the body,
and life everlasting. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.gloriaPai.name">Glory be to the Father</string>
    <string name="oracao.gloriaPai">
Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit. 
As it was in the beginning, is now, and ever shall be, world without end. 

Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.credoNiceia.name">Nicene Creed</string>
    <string name="oracao.credoNiceia">
		We believe in one God,
the Father, the Almighty,
maker of heaven and earth,
of all that is, seen and unseen. 

We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,
the only Son of God,
eternally begotten of the Father,
God from God, Light from Light,
true God from true God,
begotten, not made,
of one Being with the Father.
Through him all things were made.
For us and for our salvation
he came down from heaven:
by the power of the Holy Spirit
he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,
and was made man.
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;
he suffered death and was buried.
On the third day he rose again
in accordance with the Scriptures;
he ascended into heaven
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,
and his kingdom will have no end. 

We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,
who proceeds from the Father and the Son.
With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.
He has spoken through the Prophets.
We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
We look for the resurrection of the dead,
and the life of the world to come. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas.name">Canticle of the Creatures</string>
    <string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas">
		Highest, omnipotent good Lord!
Yours are the praises, the glory, and the honour
And all blessing
To you, alone, Most High, do they belong.
No human lips are worthy
To pronounce Your name.

Praised be You, my Lord with all Your creatures
Especially our brother, Master Sun
Who brings the day and the light
that warms us he that is beautiful and radiant
In all his splendour!
He brings meaning of You, O Most High..

Praised be You, my Lord
For Sister Moon and the Stars;
In the heavens You have made them
Precious and beautiful.
Praised be You, my Lord
Through Brothers Wind
And air, and clouds and storms,
And all the weather,
Through which You give sustenance Your creatures.
.
Praised be You, my Lord
For Sister Water;
So very useful, and humble
And precious, and chaste.
Praised be You, my Lord
For Brother Fire,
Through whom you brighten the night.
He who is beautiful and gay
And vigorous and strong.

Praised be You, my Lord
For our sister Mother Earth
Who feeds and governs us,
And produces various fruits
And coloured flowers and plants
Praised be You, my Lord
For those who forgive out of love for You;
And endure sickness and trial.
Happy those who endure in peace
For by you, Most High, they shall be crowned.

Praised be You, my Lord
For our Sister Bodily Death,
From whose embrace no living person can escape.
Woe to those who die in mortal sin!
Happy those she finds
Doing your most holy will.
The second death can do no harm to them!
Praise and bless my Lord
And give thanks
And serve him with great humility.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.espirito.santo.name">Prayer to the Holy Spirit</string>
    <string name="oracao.espirito.santo">
		Come Holy Spirit, fill the hearts of your
		faithful
		and kindle in them the fire of Your love.
		\n
		Send forth Thy Spirit and
		they shall be created, and you renew the face of the earth.
		\n
		Let us
		pray:
		God, who
		instructed the hearts of your faithful to the Light of
		Spirit
		Holy
		Do we appreciate all things righteously, according to the
		same
		Spirit
		And always Let us enjoy His consolation, through Christ our
		Lord.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.ato.contricao.name">Act of Contrition</string>
    <string name="oracao.ato.contricao">
		Forgive me my sins, O Lord, forgive me my sins;
the sins of my youth, the sins of my age, the sins of my soul,
the sins of my body; my idle sins, my serious voluntary sins;
the sins I know, the sins I do not know; the sins I have concealed
for so long, and which are now hidden from my memory.

I am truly sorry for every sin, mortal and venial,
for all the sins of my childhood up to the present hour.

I know my sins have wounded Thy Tender Heart,
O My Savior, let me be freed from the bonds of evil through
the most bitter Passion of My Redeemer. Amen.

O My Jesus, forget and forgive what I have been. Amen. 
		Amen
	</string>

</resources>