<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="oracao.santoexpedito.name">Prayer to Saint Expedite</string>
    <string name="oracao.santoexpedito">
		My Saint Expedite of urgent and just causes, please intercede for me with Our Lord Jesus Christ.
      Succor me in this hour of affliction and despair, my Saint Expedite. You who are a Holy warrior, You who are the Saint of the afflicted, You who are the Saint of the desperate, you who are the Saint of urgent causes, Protect me, Help me, Give me Strength, Courage and Serenity.

      Hear my plea. ____________ (Clearly express what you want, and ask him to find a way to get it to you.)

      My Saint Expedite, help me to prevail through these difficult hours, protect me from all those who want to harm me, respond to my plea with urgency. Bring me back to the state of peace and        tranquillity, my Saint Expedite. I will be grateful to you for the rest of my life and I will speak your name to all those who have faith.
     (Now promise to give Saint Expedite a specific offering when your desire is granted.)
     Amen.
    (Say one Our Father, one Holy Mary, and make the sign of the cross.)

    (Be sure to provide the offering you promised if Saint Expedite grants your petition)
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.meninojesusdepraga.name">Prayer to the Infant Jesus of Prague</string>
    <string name="oracao.meninojesusdepraga">
		O Jesus, Who said, "Ask and you shall receive, seek and you shall find, knock
		and it shall be opened to you," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I knock, I seek, I ask that my prayer be answered.  (Mention your request)

      O Jesus, Who said, "All that you ask of the Father in My Name He will grant you," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I humbly and urgently ask Your Father in Your Name that my prayer be granted.  (Mention your request.)

      O Jesus, Who said, "Heaven and earth will pass away, but My word shall not pass," through the intercession of Mary, Your most holy Mother, I feel confident that my prayer will be granted.  (Mention your request)

      Amen
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saojorge.name">Prayer of Saint George</string>
    <string name="oracao.saojorge">
		O Saint George, my Holy Warrior, invincible faith
		in God, which brings
		your face in the hope and confidence, open my
		ways. I will walk
		dress and armed with your arms so that my feet do not
		have enemies
		reach me, and do not catch hands, with eyes to see, and I
		do not even
		thoughts may have to make me harm. Firearms my body
		not
		reach, knives and spears break without my body reach,
		ropes and chains
		to break out my body without the tie. glorious
		St. George, on behalf of
		God, extend your shield and your mighty
		weapons, defend me with your
		strength and greatness. Help me to overcome
		all despondency and achieve
		grace I ask (request).
		Give me courage and hope, strengthen my faith
		and auxiliai me this
		need.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saomiguel.name">Prayer of St. Michael the Archangel</string>
    <string name="oracao.saomiguel">
		Saint Michael the Archangel,
      defend us in battle.
      Be our protection against the wickedness and snares of the devil.
      May God rebuke him, we humbly pray;
      and do Thou, O Prince of the Heavenly Host -
      by the Divine Power of God -
      cast into hell, satan and all the evil spirits,
      who roam throughout the world seeking the ruin of souls.

      Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.almadecristo.name">Soul of Christ</string>
    <string name="oracao.almadecristo">
		Soul of Christ, santify me.
		Body of Christ, save me.
		Blood of Christ, inebriate me.
		Water from the side of Christ, wash me.
		Passion of Christ, strengthen me.
		O good Jesus, hear me.
		Within your wounds, hide me.
		Never let me be separated from you.
		From the malignant enemy, defend me.
		At the hour of death, call me;
		and bid me come to you.
		That with your saints I may praise you
		forever and ever.

Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.saofrancisco.name">Prayer of St. Francis</string>
    <string name="oracao.saofrancisco">
		Lord, make me an instrument of your peace.
		Where there is hatred, let me sow love;
		where there is injury,pardon;
		where there is doubt, faith;
		where there is despair, hope;
		where there is darkness, light;
		and where there is sadness, joy.
		
		
		O Divine Master, grant that I may not so much seek
		to be consoled as to console;
		to be understood as to understand;
		to be loved as to love.
		For it is in giving that we receive;
		it is in pardoning that we are pardoned;
		and it is in dying that we are born to eternal life. Amen 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.avemaria.name">Hail Mary</string>
    <string name="oracao.avemaria">
		Hail Mary, full of grace.
		Our Lord is with thee.
		Blessed art thou among women,
		and blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
		Jesus.
		Holy Mary, Mother of God,
		pray for us sinners,
		now and at the hour of our death.
		Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.painosso.name">Our Father</string>
    <string name="oracao.painosso">
		Our Father, Who is in heaven,
		Holy is Your Name;
		Your kingdom come,
		Your will be done,
		on earth as it is in heaven.
		Give us this day our daily bread,
		and forgive us our sins,
		as we forgive those who sin against us;
		and lead us not into temptation,
		but deliver us from evil. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.salveRainha.name">Hail Holy Queen</string>
    <string name="oracao.salveRainha">
		Hail, holy Queen, Mother of mercy, hail, our life, our sweetness and our hope. To thee do we cry, poor banished children of Eve: to thee do we send up our sighs, mourning and weeping in this vale of tears. Turn then, most gracious Advocate, thine eyes of mercy toward us, and after this our exile, show unto us the blessed fruit of thy womb, Jesus, O merciful, O loving, O sweet Virgin Mary! Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.credo.name">The Apostles Creed</string>
    <string name="oracao.credo">
		I believe in God,
		the Father Almighty,
		Creator of Heaven and earth.
		
		I believe in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord,
		who was conceived by the Holy Spirit,
		born of the Virgin Mary,
		suffered under Pontius Pilate,
		was crucified, died and was buried.
		He descended to the dead.
		On the third day, He rose again.
		He ascended to Heaven and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
		He will come again to judge the living and the dead.
		
		I believe in the Holy Spirit,
		the Holy Catholic Church,
		the communion of saints,
		the forgiveness of sins,
		the resurrection of the body,
		and life everlasting. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.gloriaPai.name">Glory be to the Father</string>
    <string name="oracao.gloriaPai">
		Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit. 
		As it was in the beginning, is now, and ever shall be, world without end. 
		
		Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.credoNiceia.name">Nicene Creed</string>
    <string name="oracao.credoNiceia">
		We believe in one God,
		the Father, the Almighty,
		maker of heaven and earth,
		of all that is, seen and unseen. 
		
		We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,
		the only Son of God,
		eternally begotten of the Father,
		God from God, Light from Light,
		true God from true God,
		begotten, not made,
		of one Being with the Father.
		Through him all things were made.
		For us and for our salvation
		he came down from heaven:
		by the power of the Holy Spirit
		he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,
		and was made man.
		For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;
		he suffered death and was buried.
		On the third day he rose again
		in accordance with the Scriptures;
		he ascended into heaven
		and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
		He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,
		and his kingdom will have no end. 
		
		We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,
		who proceeds from the Father and the Son.
		With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.
		He has spoken through the Prophets.
		We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.
		We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
		We look for the resurrection of the dead,
		and the life of the world to come. Amen. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas.name">Canticle of the Creatures</string>
    <string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas">
		Highest, omnipotent good Lord!
		Yours are the praises, the glory, and the honour
		And all blessing
		To you, alone, Most High, do they belong.
		No human lips are worthy
		To pronounce Your name.
		
		Praised be You, my Lord with all Your creatures
		Especially our brother, Master Sun
		Who brings the day and the light
		that warms us he that is beautiful and radiant
		In all his splendour!
		He brings meaning of You, O Most High..
		
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For Sister Moon and the Stars;
		In the heavens You have made them
		Precious and beautiful.
		Praised be You, my Lord
		Through Brothers Wind
		And air, and clouds and storms,
		And all the weather,
		Through which You give sustenance Your creatures.
		.
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For Sister Water;
		So very useful, and humble
		And precious, and chaste.
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For Brother Fire,
		Through whom you brighten the night.
		He who is beautiful and gay
		And vigorous and strong.
		
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For our sister Mother Earth
		Who feeds and governs us,
		And produces various fruits
		And coloured flowers and plants
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For those who forgive out of love for You;
		And endure sickness and trial.
		Happy those who endure in peace
		For by you, Most High, they shall be crowned.
		
		Praised be You, my Lord
		For our Sister Bodily Death,
		From whose embrace no living person can escape.
		Woe to those who die in mortal sin!
		Happy those she finds
		Doing your most holy will.
		The second death can do no harm to them!
		Praise and bless my Lord
		And give thanks
		And serve him with great humility.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.espirito.santo.name">Prayer to the Holy Spirit</string>
    <string name="oracao.espirito.santo">
		Come Holy Spirit, fill the hearts of your
		faithful
		and kindle in them the fire of Your love.
		\n
		Send forth Thy Spirit and
		they shall be created, and you renew the face of the earth.
		\n
		Let us
		pray:
		God, who
		instructed the hearts of your faithful to the Light of
		Spirit
		Holy
		Do we appreciate all things righteously, according to the
		same
		Spirit
		And always Let us enjoy His consolation, through Christ our
		Lord.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.ato.contricao.name">Act of Contrition</string>
    <string name="oracao.ato.contricao">
		Forgive me my sins, O Lord, forgive me my sins;
		the sins of my youth, the sins of my age, the sins of my soul,
		the sins of my body; my idle sins, my serious voluntary sins;
		the sins I know, the sins I do not know; the sins I have concealed
		for so long, and which are now hidden from my memory.
		
		I am truly sorry for every sin, mortal and venial,
		for all the sins of my childhood up to the present hour.
		
		I know my sins have wounded Thy Tender Heart,
		O My Savior, let me be freed from the bonds of evil through
		the most bitter Passion of My Redeemer. Amen.
		
		O My Jesus, forget and forgive what I have been. 
		\n
		Amen
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.padrePio.name">Prayer after Communion (Padre Pio)</string>
    <string name="oracao.padrePio">
		Stay with me, Lord, because your presence is required not to have 
		You know how easily ofender.Tu abandono.Stay with me, Lord, 
		for I am weak and I need Your strength to not fall so vezes.Fica, 
		Lord, with me, for You are my life and without you discouraged in 
		fervor.Stay with me, Lord, for You are my light and without You 
		trevas.Stay in with me, Lord, for giving me the know 
		Your will.Stay with me, Lord, to hear your voice and Te 
		siga.Fica with me, Lord, for I want to love you very much and always be in 
		Your companion.Stay with me, Lord, if thou hast is faithful.Stay, 
		Lord, with me, as though my soul is very poor, want 
		Thee to be a place of consolation, a shrine of amor.Fica, Lord, 
		me, as it is afternoon and the day is declining, that is, spends his life, 
		approaching death, the Judgement and eternity, and we need to redouble 
		my strength, lest they faint on the way, and, therefore, 
		need Ti.Make up late and coming death! afflict me the ... 
		darkness, the temptations, the dryness, the feathers and crosses! I 
		You need to exyle.Stay tonight with me, Lord, because 
		tonight and the dangers of life, I need Ti.You know, 
		Lord, as Thy disciples in the breaking of bread, that is, that the union 
		Eucharist is the light that will dispel my darkness, the force that I 
		holds and only happiness of my heart.Fica with me, Lord, 
		therefore, when death comes, I want to be united with Thee, if not 
		in a sacramental manner the holy communion, at least by grace and 
		amor.Fica, Lord, I ask you comigo.Não Thy divine consolation, because 
		not deserve, but the gift of your presence santíssima.Oh!, Yes, that.
		Stay Lord, with me.I only sought you, your love, your grace, 
		Your will, Your heart, your spirit, because I love you, and do not 
		ask no reward besides the increase of solid and love.Practical love
		.Love Thee with all my heart on earth, to continue to love you 
		perfectly during all eternity. 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.lembraivos.name">Remember (St. Bernard)</string>
    <string name="oracao.lembraivos">
		Remember, O Virgin Mary, 
		you never heard 
		that some of those 
		they have resorted to your protection, 
		implored your assistance, 
		and claimed your help, 
		was left unaided. 
		I excited because of this confidence, 
		to thee, O Virgin of virgins, 
		resort as the Mother, 
		from you I\'m worth, and 
		groaning under the weight of my sins, 
		I prostrate at Your Feet. 
		Despise not my petitions, 
		O Mother of the Son of God made man, 
		Deem worthy but 
		conducive to hear them 
		and achieve what I pray you.
		\n
		Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.cincoChagas.name">Devotion to the Five Wounds Jesus Christ </string>
    <string name="oracao.cincoChagas"> 
		Opening Prayer 
		\n
		While standing on his knees before your 
		sacred image. 
		Oh! My Saviour, my conscience tells me that I have 
		I been to you 
		nailed on the cross with these hands, every time 
		I have dared 
		committing a mortal sin. My God, my love and 
		all, worthy of all 
		worship and love seeing how many times I ye 
		cumulated 
		blessings, I find myself on my knees, convinced that I can still 
		repair 
		injuries that I have offended. 
		At least I can 
		sympathize, I can give You thanks for all that ye 
		done for me. 
		Forgive me, my Lord. 
		So with the heart and say with their lips: 
		Forgive me, my Lord. 
		\n\n 
		The Wound of the Left Foot: 
		\n
		Holy Wound 
		the left foot of my Jesus, adore. 
		It pains me, good Jesus, to see You 
		painful suffering that penalty. 
		I thank you, Oh! Jesus in my soul, 
		for ye have suffered so 
		unspeakable pain to stop me in my car 
		the precipice, 
		suffering because of Thee the throbbing of my thorns 
		sins. 
		I offer the Eternal Father, suffering and love of your 
		Most Holy Humanity 
		to compensate for my sins, I hate to 
		sincere contrition. 
		\n\n 
		The Wound of the right foot: 
		\n
		Holy Wound of the foot 
		right to my Jesus, adore. 
		It pains me, Good 
		Jesus see you suffer 
		painful punishment. I thank you, 
		Oh! Jesus 
		of my life, for that 
		love that suffered such unspeakable pain, 
		shedding blood to punish my 
		sinful desires and walked in 
		pro pleasure. 
		I offer the Eternal Father, 
		suffering and the love of your 
		Most Holy Humanity, 
		and ask for the grace of 
		crying my transgressions and 
		to persevere in 
		path of good, fulfilling 
		faithfully the 
		commandments of God. 
		\n\n 
		The Wound of the Left Hand: 
		\n
		Holy Wound of your hand 
		left of my Jesus, adore. 
		It pains me, Good 
		Jesus see you suffer 
		painful punishment. 
		I thank you, Oh! Jesus 
		my life, because by 
		ye me your love 
		Rid me to suffer 
		flagellation and the eternal 
		conviction, I have 
		deserved because of my 
		sins. 
		I offer the 
		Eternal Father, suffering and the love of your 
		Humanity and holy 
		I pray help me to make good use of my 
		strength and my life, 
		to produce fruits worthy of glory and life 
		eternal and so disarm the 
		righteous wrath of God. 
		\n\n 
		The Wound of the Right Hand: 
		\n
		Holy Wound of your hand 
		right hand of my Jesus, adore. 
		It pains me, Good 
		Jesus see you suffer 
		painful punishment. 
		I thank you, Oh! Jesus 
		my life, for having me 
		accumulated 
		benefits and graces, and this despite 
		of my obstinacy in 
		sin. 
		I offer the Eternal Father the pain and the 
		love of Thy most holy 
		Humanity and pray help me to do everything 
		to greater honor and glory 
		of God. 
		\n\n 
		The Sacred Wound of the Chest: 
		\n
		Holy Wound of the Sacred 
		Breast of my Jesus, adore. 
		It hurts me, 
		Good Jesus, see you suffer so 
		great injury. 
		I thank you, Oh! Good 
		Jesus, I love the 
		have, by allowing 
		You opened the chest, 
		with a cast and so 
		shed the last drop 
		of blood, 
		redeem me. 
		I offer the Eternal Father 
		this offer and the love of your 
		Most Holy Humanity, 
		for my 
		can find in your soul 
		a heart pierced 
		Safe Haven. 
		\n 
		Amen 
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.magnificat.name">Magnificat</string>
    <string name="oracao.magnificat">
		My soul doth magnify the Lord my 
		And my spirit rejoices in God my Savior! 
		Because the lowliness of his poor servant; 
		henceforth all generations shall call me blessed, 
		Because the Almighty has done great things for me, and holy is his name! 
		He has shown strength with his arm 
		Disconcerted the hearts of the proud 
		Overthrew the throne the powerful, 
		and exalted the humble. 
		He fills the hungry, 
		and sent the rich away empty. 
		He protects Israel, his servant, 
		remembered his mercy; 
		as promised to our fathers, 
		to Abraham and his seed for ever. 
		Glory to the Father, the Son, and Holy Spirit. 
		As it was in the beginning is now and ever, amen 
		The mighty has done great things for me, and holy is his name!
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.santoAnjo.name">Holy angel of the Lord</string>
    <string name="oracao.santoAnjo">
		Holy angel of the Lord 
		my zealous keeper. 
		If you entrusted me with the divine mercy, 
		I always governs, 
		forbid, 
		I rule, 
		enlighten me. 
		\n
		Amen.
	</string>
    <string name="oracao.ladainhaNossaSenhora.name">Litany of Our Lady</string>
    <string name="oracao.ladainhaNossaSenhora">Lord, have mercy on us. \n 
		Jesus Christ, have mercy on us. \n 
		Lord, have mercy on us. \n 
		Christ, hear us. \n 
		Jesus Christ, graciously hear us. \n 
		Heavenly Father that you are God, have mercy on us. \n 
		Son, Redeemer of the world that you are God, have mercy on us. \n 
		Holy Spirit are God, have mercy on us. \n 
		Holy Trinity one God, have mercy on us. \n 
		Holy Mary, pray for us. \n 
		Holy Mother of God, \n 
		Holy Virgin of virgins, \n 
		Mother of Jesus Christ, \n 
		Mother of divine grace, \n 
		Mother most pure, \n 
		Mother most chaste, \n 
		Immaculate Mother, \n 
		Mother undefiled, \n 
		Mom kind, \n 
		Mother most admirable, \n 
		Mother of Good Counsel, \n 
		Mother of the Creator, \n 
		Mother of the Saviour, \n 
		Virgin most prudent, \n 
		Virgin most venerable, \n 
		Virgin most renowned, \n 
		Virgin most powerful, \n 
		Virgin most merciful, \n 
		Virgin most faithful, \n 
		Mirror of justice, \n 
		Seat of wisdom, \n 
		Cause of our joy, \n 
		Spiritual vessel, \n 
		Vessel worthy of honor, \n 
		Singular vessel of devotion, \n 
		Mystical rose, \n 
		Tower of David, \n 
		Tower of ivory, \n 
		House of gold, \n 
		Ark of the Covenant, \n 
		Gate of Heaven, \n 
		Morning Star \n 
		Health of the Sick, \n 
		Refuge of sinners, \n 
		Comforter of the afflicted, \n 
		Help of Christians, \n 
		Queen of Angels \n 
		Queen of Patriarchs, \n 
		Queen of Prophets, \n 
		Queen of the Apostles, \n 
		Queen of Martyrs, \n 
		Queen of Confessors, \n 
		Queen of Virgins, \n 
		Queen of All Saints \n 
		Queen conceived without original sin, \n 
		Queen assumed into Heaven, \n 
		Queen of the most holy Rosary, \n 
		Queen of Peace, \n 
		\n \n 
		Lamb of God who taketh away the sins of the world, spare us, O Lord. \n 
		Lamb of God who taketh away the sins of the world, graciously hear us, O Lord. \n 
		Lamb of God who taketh away the sins of the world, have mercy on us. \n 
		\n \n 
		Pray for us, holy Mother of God. 
		\n 
		To be worthy of the promises of Christ. 
		\n \n 
		Let us pray. Lord God, we beseech Thee to grant unto thy servants 
		perpetual health of mind and body, and which, by the glorious intercession of the 
		Blessed Virgin Mary, we are free from the sorrow of 
		Let us enjoy the century and eternal joy. Through Christ our Lord. 
		\n 
		Amen
	</string>

</resources>