<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="oracao.saofrancisco.name">Prayer of St. Francis</string>
	<string name="oracao.saofrancisco">
		Lord, make me an instrument of your Peace \n
		Where there is hatred let me sow love,
		Where there is injury, let me sow
		Sorry.
		Where there is discord, I may bring the Union
		Where there is doubt,
		I may bring faith
		Where there is error, I may bring truth.
		Where there
		Despair, let me bring hope.
		Where there is sadness, I may bring
		Joy.
		Where there is darkness, light to light!
		\n
		O Divine Master,
		I do
		find more:
		comfort, be comforted;
		understand, to be
		understood;
		love and be loved.
		It is in giving that we receive.
		Forgiving that one is forgiven and
		it is in dying that we live for life
		eternal!
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.avemaria.name">Ave Maria</string>
	<string name="oracao.avemaria">
		Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.
		Blessed art thou among
		women and blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
		Jesus.
		\n
		Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners now and at the
		our hours
		death.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.painosso.name"> Our Father </string>
	<string name="oracao.painosso">
		Our Father which art in heaven, hallowed be
		your name, come to thy kingdom and thy will be done,
		on earth as in heaven.
		\n
		The day our daily bread Give us this day;
		and forgive us our trespasses
		as we forgive those who have
		offended. Let us not fall into
		temptation, but deliver us from all
		poorly.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.salveRainha.name">Salve Regina</string>
	<string name="oracao.salveRainha">
		Hail, holy Queen, Mother of mercy, our life, sweetness,
		our hope, hail! To you we cry, poor banished children of Eve The
		Sighs, mourning and weeping in this valley of tears. Come, then,
		our advocate, thine eyes of mercy toward us Volvo, and,
		after this our exile, show us Jesus, the blessed fruit of thy
		womb, O clement, O loving, O sweet Virgin Mary.
		\n
		Pray for
		us, Holy Mother of God, to be worthy of reaching the
		promises of Christ.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.credo.name"> Creed </string>
	<string name="oracao.credo">
		I believe in God the Father Almighty, maker of heaven and
		the earth and in Jesus
		Christ, His only Son, our Lord, which was
		conceived by the
		Holy Spirit, born of the Virgin Mary, suffered
		under Pontius Pilate,
		was crucified, dead and buried, He descended into hell
		the dead;
		rose again the third day, ascended into heaven and is seated at the
		right
		God the Father Almighty, whence He shall come to judge the living and
		the dead;
		I believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy catholic Church, the
		communion of
		Saints, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body
		in life
		eternal.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.gloriaPai.name"> Glory to the Father </string>
	<string name="oracao.gloriaPai">
		Glory to the Father, Son and Holy Spirit!
		So as it was in the beginning, now and forever.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.credoNiceia.name"> Nicene Creed </string>
	<string name="oracao.credoNiceia">
		We believe in one God, Father Almighty, Maker of
		Heaven and earth, of all things visible and invisible.
		\n
		I believe in a
		one Lord, Jesus Christ, only Son of God, born
		the Father before
		all ages, God from God, Light of Light, God
		God\'s true
		true, begotten, not made, consubstantial with the
		Father by whom all
		things were made. For us men and for
		our salvation,
		down
		of heaven and was incarnate by the Holy Spirit in
		the Virgin
		Mary and
		became man. Was crucified also for us
		under Pontius
		Pilate, suffered
		and was buried. Raised on the third
		days,
		according to the Scriptures, and
		He ascended into heaven and is seated at the
		right
		the Father Ede come again,
		in glory to judge the living
		and
		dead, and his kingdom will have no
		end.
		\n
		I believe in the Holy Spirit, Lord
		Giver of Life who proceeds from the Father and
		of
		Son;
		With the Father and the Son is
		worshiped and glorified, who spoke
		to
		prophets. I believe in one church,
		holy, catholic and apostolic.
		Professed
		one baptism for the remission
		of sins. We look for
		resurrection
		of
		dead and the life of the world
		is to come.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas.name">Canticle of the Creatures</string>
	<string name="oracao.cantico.criaturas">
		Most High, omnipotent, good Lord,
		thee the praise,
		glory, honor and all blessing.
		\n
		To you alone, Most High, should they be
		render
		and no man is worthy of you name.
		\n
		Praised be Thou, O my
		Lord with all your creatures,
		especially my lord Brother
		Sun,
		which makes the day and he enlightens us.
		And he is beautiful and radiant with
		splendor:
		you, Most High, he gives us the image.
		\n
		Praise
		Thou, O my Lord, through Sister Moon and Stars:
		kindled in the sky,
		clear and precious and beautiful.
		\n
		Praised be my Lord, through Brother
		Wind
		and the Air, and clouds, and Sereno, and all the time,
		by whom you give to
		your creatures sustenance.
		\n
		Praised be my Lord, through Sister
		Water
		that is so useful and humble and precious and chaste.
		\n
		Be praised, O
		my Lord, through Brother Fire,
		by which brighten up the night:
		and it is beautiful, and
		playful and robust and strong.
		\n
		Praised be Thou, O my Lord, for our
		Sister Mother Earth,
		that sustains and governs us, producing varied fruits,
		with colorful flowers, and vegetables.
		\n
		Praised be Thou, O my Lord, for
		those who grant pardon for love
		and bear infirmity and tribulation.
		\n
		Blessed are those who support them in peace,
		as for thee,
		Most High, will be crowned.
		\n
		Praised be my Lord, for our
		Sister Death,
		to which no living man can escape:
		Alas
		those who die in mortal sin!
		Blessed are those who
		fulfill your holy will,
		the second death because they do not
		hurt.
		\n
		Praise and bless my Lord and give Him thanks
		and serve the
		with great humility ...
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.espirito.santo.name">Prayer Holy Spirit</string>
	<string name="oracao.espirito.santo">
		Come Holy Spirit, fill the hearts of your
		faithful and enkindle in them the fire of Your love.
		\n
		Send forth Thy Spirit and
		they shall be created, and you renew the face of the earth.
		\n
		Let us pray:
		God, who
		instructed the hearts of your faithful to the Light of Spirit
		Holy
		Do we appreciate all things righteously, according to the same
		Spirit
		And always Let us enjoy His consolation, through Christ our Lord.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>

	<string name="oracao.ato.contricao.name">Act of Contrition</string>
	<string name="oracao.ato.contricao">
		My God, I repent with all my heart for you
		Have offended, because
		you are so good and kind. I promise, with your
		grace, try me
		be good. My Jesus, mercy!
		\n
		Mr.
		my Jesus Christ, true God and man, Creator and my Redeemer:
		You because you are who you are, supremely good and lovable about
		all things, and because I love you and cherish, weighs me, Lord,
		all my heart, that he hath offended, I grieve also have
		lost heaven and deserved hell, and I suggest strongly, helped
		with the aid of Your divine grace, correct me and never Vos
		make the offense. I hope to obtain pardon of my sins by
		Your infinite mercy.
		\n
		Amen
	</string>
</resources>